

Jamie Davies

Full Stack Developer

Mobile: 07718061934 - Portfolio: iamjamiedavies.com

Summary

I'm a full stack developer who's great at building beautiful functional products from the ground up. I started programming at the age of 8, and at 14 I founded my first funded start-up.

I have a massive passion for hackathons, which has given me ability to work with and learn new technologies, while at the same time rapidly building awesome prototypes.

I also **love** data, my current position at TalkLife has given me access to a wealth of rich data that i've been able to do incredibly fun, but also useful things with. Before I started at TalkLife the only overview that had over their community, was a badly configured Google Analytics account and a flags email inbox. I saw this when I joined and knew I wanted to improve it.

Over the last 2 years the main project i've worked on is building their admin dashboard. Now all of TalkLife's analytics, moderation and user management is able to be accessed and acted on in one place, more efficiently and with much better accountability and auditing.

Experience

Co-Founder and Developer

Doorpass

2016 - Current

Doorpass is a cloud management solution for managing your employees and their permissions on external cloud services. I've been working on it as a side project with a friend since March '16

- Built a modular scalable integration system that standardises user management APIs across many different platforms.
- Built automated scraper bots to manage sub-users on external platforms that don't expose a public API for managing users

Developer

TalkLife

2015 - Current

- Built a confidential messaging service that connects patients to licensed therapists for a low monthly cost enabling anyone access to a therapist when they need them the most
- Designed and built an admin/overview dashboard that views and controls all the different TalkLife related services
- I come up with and prototype new ideas, using different technologies to test their feasibility and demo to investors.
- Worked alongside bright minds at MIT, Harvard and Microsoft Research to work on an incredible research project involving mental health and suicide intervention.
- Built multiple internal tools used in processing large amounts of data to assist in tasks like moderation and suicide intervention.

Co-Founder and Development

whatleads.to (former CauseHub.io)

2013 - 2015

- Founded in December 2013 and pitched to receive incubator funding from Bethnal Green Ventures.
- Built a scalable web app and API able to handle thousands of concurrent connections.
- Built the entire back-end and dynamic front-end codebase to work on the distributed infrastructure while keeping load times and bandwidth low
- (Ref: Sanjay Poyzer, +44 789 512 3673, sanjay@whatleads.to)

Waiter

The Rotisserie

2012 - 2015

- Working at my fathers restaurant on the service floor as a Waiter, responsible for taking orders, interacting with customers, resolving problems and preparing desserts.
- (Ref: Ian Davies, +44 773 674 1314, ian@therotisserie.co.uk)

Intern

Innovation Warehouse

Summer 2013

- Summer internship / work experience at a co-working space.
- Worked on the website and also every day administrative work around the office.
- Worked with multiple startups on helping test their ideas and resolve problems in the workspace.
- Assisted with organising and running events with 100+ attendees
- Helped maintain and improve the large and complex network

Freelance Admin Work

Comotion

Helping with administrative work

Summer 2013

Education Mill Hill School

GCSEs

Computer Science A*

Maths A

Statistics A

Separate Science (Physics, Biology, Chemistry) A B C

Design Technology A

English C

AS-Levels (Ceiling grade A)

Computer Science A Maths A Physics A (predicted) Design Technology B

A2-Levels (This year)

Computer Science A* (Predicted) Maths A* (Predicted) Physics A (Predicted)

Achievements Work

- Built a start-up at the age of 14, which received investments, grants and multiple awards, as well as media attention on The Guardian and the BBC One Show.
- First year winner of the Duke of York's IDEA award for young entrepreneurs
- Worked alongside the bright minds at MIT, Harvard and Microsoft Research on a world first research project involving mental health and suicide intervention.

Other Activities

- Volunteered in a school in Southern India for 3 weeks over summer 2016 teaching conversational english to underprivileged kids from a local rural town
- A keen cricketer, scuba diver, photographer, climber and office ping pong star.
- Currently training for a private pilot license as i've always had a passion for planes and aviation